Roy Eugene

Software Engineer

🗣 Lower Kabete, 00100 Nairobi, Kenya 🛛 roy.eugenes000@gmail.com 📞 0740682925

Professional Summary

Full Stack Software Engineer with five years of experience in application design and development, data modeling, cross-browser user interface design, and programming, translating business requirements to technical specifications, Project management, and team building. Works well under pressure and consistently meets deadlines and targets while delivering high quality work.

Skills

Programming languages

JavaScript, Python, C

Markup Languages

HTML5, XML

CSS Frameworks

Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS

Source Control Tools

Git

Operating Systems

Linux, Windows, Android

Build Tools

NPM, Yarn, gulp.js, Jekyll, Git, Jenkins, Babel

Standards

ES6, HTTP, REST, TCP/IP, WebSocket, APIs

Excellent Organizational Skills

Excellent Research Skills

Design and diagnostic skills

Proactive and team player

Proficient Technical Knowhow

JavaScript Libraries

React.js, jQuery, AJAX

StyleSheets

CSS5, SCSS, Flexbox

SQL Database Systems

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle

Containerization

Docker, Kubernetes

Data-Interchange Format

JSON

CMS

WordPress, Webflow, Wix

Web Servers

NGINX, Apache HTTPD, Apache Tomcat, GlassFish

Proven Leadership Skills

Interpersonal and communication skills

Critical and Creative Thinking

Fast Learner able to apply acquired knowledge

effectively

Professional Experience

02/2017 - 11/2020 Mombasa, Kenya

Front-End Developer, SwahiliBox

- Managed website development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Developed and integrated custom themes into WordPress.
- Developed frontend components with JavaScript, React.js and libraries such as Bootstrap.

• Worked closely with programmers and clients to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality

06/2017 – 12/2019 Nairobi, Kenya

Graphic Designer, *Twiice Tech*

- Conceptualized and designed print pieces for various organizations
- Managed design projects.
- Transitioned website to a unified look under a CMS system, improving service to customers.
- Created 30+ marketing content and social media campaigns to boost company reach through content ideation and implementation schedules.
- Designed aesthetically-pleasing branding and agent advertising

Education

05/2022 – present Nairobi, Kenya	Software Engineering, <i>Holberton Schoo</i> Full-stack Engineering	l
09/2016 – 11/2020 Mombasa, Kenya	Bachelor of Business and Information Technology, Technical University of Mombasa	
Interests		
 Machine Learning 	 Al and Robotics 	 Neural Networks
• Cloud Computing		
Languages		
• English	• Spanish	• Chinese

References

Brian Gache, *Product Manager*, Dealcity Private Limited b.gache@dealcity.co.ke, 0706936267

Francis Mwakidoshi, *Software Engineer - OSS Planning and Automation*, Safaricom PLC francismwakidoshi@gmail.com, 0708009360